Contact

jeffjohnson335@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-johnson60602 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Banking Capital Markets Finance

Certifications

Series 79 - Investment Banking Representative

Series 63

Jeff Johnson

Senior Vice President at U.S. Bank

Greater Chicago Area

Summary

A respected senior banker responsible for leading the efforts to expand U.S. Bank's automotive banking market share with OEM's and suppliers. Expertise in client and business development. Strong experience with credit underwriting. Ability to develop senior level company relationships. Outstanding drive, initiative, and motivation. Years of experience in prospecting, uptiering and successfully cross selling ancillary banking services, including foreign exchange, short-term investments, treasury management, letters of credit, debt capital markets and derivatives. Extensive financial modeling knowledge, building financial models and projections. Demonstrated ability working with HLT and EVR syndicated loans. Prestigiously named winner of the 2017 Legends of Possible Award and 2013 Summit Award, U.S. Bank's top Corporate & Commercial banking award.

FINRA - Series 79 & 63.

Experience

U.S. Bank

23 years 1 month

Senior Vice President - Corporate Banking | Automotive Division January 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months)

Chicago, IL

Bank Relationship Manager for Automotive OEM's and suppliers.

- Portfolio consists of 17 clients and credit commitments of \$1.1 billion and generates over \$14 million in annual revenue.

Senior Vice President - National Corporate Banking March 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 10 months) Chicago, IL

Portfolio had \$1.5 billion in loan commitments, \$320 million in loan outstandings and produced over \$21 million of annual revenue. Client base was IG. HY and ABL.

- Boosted the total 2017 portfolio revenue, 26%, to \$21 million.
- Grew the 2017 Capital Markets and Foreign Exchange Revenue 198%, to \$4.7 million.
- Closed on a \$149 million commitment for a \$3.65 billion acquisition financing package for a Tier 1 auto supplier.
- JLA and JBR for \$1.6 billion of 5-year, senior unsecured credit facilities for a privately held glass manufacturer.
- Added over \$1.3 million of new revenue by converting two new prospects for 2017.

Vice President - National Corporate Banking February 2010 - March 2015 (5 years 2 months) Chicago, IL

- Signed 15 new clients during tenor in Chicago office, two new credit relationships in 2014 and 10 new FX clients.
- Increased the client short-term investments by 530%, to \$1.1 billion at fiscal year-end of 2014.
- SLA and AA on a \$60 million cash secured DIP L/C facility for a Tier 1 supplier to the automotive industry during a Chapter 11 bankruptcy, resulting in over \$1 million in revenue.
- Generated over \$2 million of combined fees by participating in new syndicated senior secured exit financings for a large automotive OEM and Tier 1 suppler, both coming out of bankruptcy.

VP / AVP / Officer - National Corporate Banking July 1997 - February 2010 (12 years 8 months) Minneapolis, MN

- Expanded U.S. Bank's large corporate market share with companies located in S. Dakota and Minnesota.
- Oversaw 16 corporate banking relationships, including eight, large non-profit hospitals, generating over \$8 million in annual revenue.
- Negotiated a 2nd lien collateral position for a discretionary freight transportation credit line of a major OEM automotive manufacturer.
- SLA and AA on several major transactions including \$225 million SBPA for a large children's hospital, \$90 million of LCs for a South Dakota based health care system, and \$25 million Bridge financing, generating over \$1 in fees.

Previous roles at U.S. Bank included:

Assistant Vice President - Relationship/Portfolio Manager, Minneapolis, MN Produced over \$3 million of annual revenue for a \$350 million loan portfolio. Secured \$75 million in new loan commitments in 2004, producing over \$800,000 in fees.

Corporate Banking Officer - Relationship/Portfolio Manager-Middle Market, Minneapolis, MN

Managed a \$150 loan portfolio with investment grade and high-yield credit relationships.

Corporate Banking Associate - Middle Market, Minneapolis, MN Assisted senior bankers with underwriting, leveraged and syndicated credit facilities.

Developed cash flow and pro-forma financial projections to assess alternate financing structures

Ameriprise Financial Services, Inc. Manager - Global Operations June 1996 - July 1997 (1 year 2 months)

Managed hedge fund operations and supervised foreign, domestic, and derivative settlements for all IDS-American Express mutual funds, hedge funds, and managed portfolios.

RBC Global Asset Management (U.S.) Inc. Senior Mutual Fund Accountant November 1992 - June 1996 (3 years 8 months) Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area

RBC Global Asset Management (fka Voyageur Asset Management).

Trained and reviewed work for five accountants. Assisted manager in team leadership responsibilities for over 25 domestic and international mutual funds. Calculated daily fund NAV's and prepared financial statements along with SEC filings.

Education

University of St. Thomas - Opus College of Business MBA, Finance · (1995 - 1997)

University of Minnesota Duluth

Bachelor of Accounting, Minors: Economics and Psychology · (1988 - 1992)